https://www.arcusfoundation.org/privacy-policy/

Press Kit
News
Privacy Policy
The Arcus Foundation (“Arcus,” “we,” “us,” “our”) as a controller of personal data is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Policy describes the information we collect through our websites www.arcusfoundation.org, 2019.arcusfoundation.org (and variants thereof in the format XXXX.arcusfoundation.org), www.stateoftheapes.org, media.arcusfoundation.org (each the “Site”), how we use and share it, and how you can make choices about our use of that information.
Please note that this Privacy Policy may be amended from time to time, so please check back regularly. By using the Site after we have posted an updated Privacy Policy, you agree to that updated Privacy Policy.
By using the Site, you consent to our collection, use, and sharing of information as described in this Privacy Policy.
1. Information We Collect
2. Cookies
3. How We Use Personal Information
4. How We Share Personal Information
5. Communications and Marketing
6. Third-Party Websites
7. The Lawful Bases for Processing Personal Information
8. Your Rights with Respect to Personal Information
9. Data Retention
10. Security and Storage of Personal Information
11. Location of Servers and Transfers of Personal Information
12. Your Choices Regarding Our Use of Your Personal Information
13. Children
14. Changes to This Policy
15. Contact Us
1. Information We Collect
Information You Provide to Us
We collect personally identifiable information (“Personal Information”), such as your name, email address, mailing address and other information, when you voluntarily provide it to us. Below are the most common ways in which you would provide your Personal Information:
• When you sign up to receive emails and publications from us
• When you click on “apply for a grant”
• If you apply to an employment opportunity through the Site
• If you complete and submit an online form or survey through the Site
• In conjunction with any other place on the Site where you knowingly volunteer Personal Information
• When you register for an event
When you click to apply for a grant, you will be directed to our grants management system, operated by our Service Provider (as defined below) and used and accessed by the Foundation. Any Personal Information you provide in your grant application and in the grant application or grant administration process will be subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy, as though it was collected through the Site.
Information Automatically Collected
We may also collect information about visitors interacting with the Site. This includes the IP address of the device you use to access the Site, the browser type, the time and date of visits to the Site, and the website that referred or linked you to the Site. We may use this information to analyze how visitors use our Site so we can improve the quality of the information and services we provide. More information is set out in our Cookies Statement below.
2. Cookies Statement
We or our third-party service providers (each, a “Service Provider,” together, “Service Providers”) may collect information through cookies, web beacons, pixel tags, clear gifs or similar technologies, which are small data files placed on your computer. For example, cookies may anonymously track a user across a web session on the Site. This Site uses the following cookies for the following purposes:
Strictly Necessary Cookies
These cookies are essential to enable the user to navigate around the platform securely and to provide the user with services they have specifically requested.
Performance Cookies
Google Analytics
These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our Site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the Site from and the pages they visited. We use the information to compile statistic reports of our users’ browsing patterns so that we can improve the Site
View an overview of privacy at Google
Functionality Cookies
Session Cookie
This cookie is used to identify a user’s browser as they go from page to page on the Site. It is a session cookie, which means the cookie is deleted when you leave the Site. It is an integral part of the website software and is used to let the server know which users are on the Site at any given time and make certain parts of the Site easier to use (for example, to store page preferences such as colour scheme chosen for the duration of your visit, when you register for one of our events online or apply online for one of our trainee or placement positions).
You can control how your browser handles cookies received from Site. You can choose to refuse all cookies, or to be prompted before a cookie is saved to your hard drive, or to only accept cookies from certain websites that you designate. Information on deleting or controlling cookies is available at www.aboutcookies.org. By refusing to accept cookies from us, you may not be able to use some of the features and functionality available on our Site.
Other third-party cookies
When we provide icons and links to certain social media sites such as Facebook and Twitter, they may serve ads and collect certain information when you visit the Site. These companies may use certain information (e.g., click stream information, web browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to the Site and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third-party clear gif/web beacon to collect this information. Our systems do not recognize browser “Do Not Track” signals, but our service providers who utilize these cookies or web beacons on our Site may enable you to opt out of targeted advertising practices so please visit their websites to understand how you can control the way in which they process your information. Please see section 6 below.
3. How We Use Personal Information
We or our Service Providers (as defined below) may use your Personal Information for the following purposes:
• To send you information about publications, news, events, or opportunities that we think may be of interest to you
• To process and communicate with you about your LOI, grant, or employment application.
• To ensure and improve the quality of our Site
• To improve the content or our Site and research related to our grant making and other activities
• To notify you about substantive changes to our privacy practices
• To detect, investigate, and protect against any activities that may violate our policies or the law and to establish, defend against, or enforce any related claims
4. How We Share Personal Information
We do not rent or sell your Personal Information to any third parties.
We may share your Personal Information with our Service Providers that help us operate and provide services in connection with the Site.
We may use independent contractors or consultants to perform services for Arcus. These individuals and entities may have access to Personal Information only as needed to perform their functions and are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality of any Personal Information collected from the Site.
We also reserve the right to disclose and use Personal Information and other information in special circumstances, including to enforce this Privacy Policy or any other part of our Terms, to comply with legal process or law enforcement, to address actual or suspected illegal activity, to protect our property or rights, to protect the rights and safety of anyone, or for other reasons we determine in good faith are necessary, appropriate, or required by law. If we ever merge with, are acquired by, or otherwise consolidate with another organization, Personal Information may be transferred along with our other assets.
5. Communications and Marketing
We may use your personal data and other information to provide you with information and updates about our work, events, activities, and/or campaigns which we consider may be of interest to you.
In some jurisdictions, such as EU member states, where such communications are direct marketing there are restrictions on how we can do this. Where we contact you with such marketing via email, we will do so where you have requested the same or where you have consented or where we are otherwise allowed to do so by the applicable data privacy law of the jurisdiction in which you are based.
You can always request not to receive communications from us so please let us know by email at contact@arcusfoundation.org. Alternately, you can opt out of receiving direct marketing emails from Arcus at any time by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of our emails.
6. Third-Party Websites
The Site contains links to third-party websites, including Arcus’s social media pages (“Third-Party Sites”). Third-Party Sites may collect information about you when you interact with them through those links. If you follow any link to a Third-Party Site, you should review those sites’ privacy policies to find out how they protect your privacy. We are not responsible for Third-Party Sites or their privacy practices.
7. The Lawful Bases for Processing Personal Information
In order to comply with applicable data protection laws, in particular the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), we are required to rely on one or more lawful bases for the processing of your Personal Information. In accordance with the purposes for which we collect and use your Personal Information, as set out above, the lawful basis for processing your Personal Information will typically be one of the following:
Where you have provided your consent for us to use your Personal Information in a certain way (for example, we may ask for your consent to email you with updates about our work, services and opportunities which we consider may be of interest to you).
Where necessary so that we can comply with a legal obligation to which we are subject (for example, where we are obliged to share your Personal Information with regulatory bodies which govern our work).
Where necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request prior to entering a contract.
Where there is a legitimate interest in us doing so. In brief, the GDPR allows us to collect and use your Personal Information if it is reasonably necessary to achieve our or others’ legitimate interests (as long as that processing is fair, balanced and does not unduly impact your rights). In broad terms, our “legitimate interests” means the running of Arcus as a non-profit organization committed to LGBTQ people and great apes. Where we use your Personal Information to achieve such legitimate interests, we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative), and your rights under data protection laws. We will not use your Personal Information for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you, for example where use would be excessively intrusive in the circumstances (unless, for example, we are otherwise required to by law).
8. Your Rights with Respect to Personal Information
Persons located in the EU may have certain rights in relation to their Personal Information under the GDPR. Persons in other jurisdictions may also have certain rights in relation to their Personal Information. We will honor your requests to exercise the following rights to the extent possible and as required under the applicable law:
Right to rectification. If you believe our records of your Personal Information are inaccurate or out of date, you have the right to ask for those records to be corrected / updated. You can also ask us to check the Personal Information we hold about you to check whether it is accurate / up to date.
Right to withdraw consent. Where we rely on your consent to use your Personal Information, you have the right to withdraw that consent at any time. This includes the right to ask us to stop using your Personal Information for marketing purposes, or to unsubscribe from our email list at any time.
Right of access. You can write to us to ask for confirmation of what Personal Information we hold on you and to request a copy of that Personal Information. Provided we are satisfied that you are entitled to see the Personal Information requested and, where reasonably required, we have successfully confirmed your identity, we will provide you with your Personal Information subject to any exemptions which may apply.
Right to object. You have the right to object to processing where we are (i) processing your Personal Information in reliance on the lawful basis of legitimate interests (see section 6 above), (ii) using your Personal Information for direct marketing, or (iii) using your Personal Information for statistical purposes.
Right to erasure. You may request that we erase your personal data. We will comply, unless there is a lawful reason for not doing so. In many cases, we shall use limited Personal Information to suppress further communications with you, rather than delete it entirely, so that we can comply with your preferences.
Right to restrict. You have the right to ask for processing of your Personal Information to be restricted if there is disagreement about its accuracy or legitimate use.
Right to data portability. To the extent required by the GDPR, where we are processing your Personal Information (that you have provided to us) either (i) by relying on your consent or (ii) because such processing is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract, and in either case we are processing using automated means (i.e. with no human involvement), you may ask us to provide the Personal Information to you – or another service provider – in a commonly used machine-readable format.
Rights related to automated decision-making. You have the right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing of your Personal Information which produces legal effects on you or similarly significantly affects you, unless such a decision (i) is necessary to enter into / perform a contract between you and us / another organization; (ii) is authorized by the EU or an EU member state law to which Arcus is subject (as long as that law offers you sufficient protection); or (iii) is based on your explicit consent.
Right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority. For individuals based in the EU, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority about how we use your Personal Information. A list of the data protection authorities in each member state, including their contact details, can be found here: http://ec/europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm. For further information, please contact us using the details below.
9. Data Retention
In general, we will keep your Personal Information for as long as it is required in connection with the purpose(s) for which was collected and/or processed, unless otherwise prescribed by law.
If you request to receive no further contact from us, we will keep some basic Personal Information about you on our suppression list in order to comply with your request and avoid sending you unwanted communications in the future.
10. Security and Storage of Personal Information
We use reasonable efforts to safeguard your Personal Information. All traffic on the Site is encrypted with an SSL Certificate, including transmission of Personal Information to the Site. Of course, no transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, so you provide your Personal Information at your own risk.
11. Location of Servers and Transfers of Personal Information
Your Personal Information will be accessed and processed in the USA. In addition, your Personal Information may be transferred outside the United States to our other offices or Service Providers with locations in other countries.
Certain countries have rules relating to the transfer of personal information across borders and require us to ensure that Personal Information remains protected according to appropriate standards (for example, EU member states under the GDPR).
If you are an individual based in the EU, please note that some countries outside the EU have a lower standard of protection for Personal Information, including lower security requirements and fewer rights for individuals.
If you have any questions about the transfer of your Personal Information, please contact us using the details below.
12. Your Choices Regarding Our Use of Your Personal Information
If you wish to review, update, correct, or remove the information we have for you, please email contact@arcusfoundation.org.
If you no longer wish to receive communications from us, you can also unsubscribe by clicking on the “unsubscribe” button in any email communication you receive from us.
Some browsers have incorporated Do Not Track (“DNT”) preferences. As there is not yet an industry-standard DNT protocol on how to interpret DNT signals, we do not honor DNT signals from browsers at this time. However, you may refuse or delete cookies to prevent tracking activities.
13. Children
The Site is directed at an adult (i.e. 18 and over) audience and we do not knowingly collect information from or about children. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under 13 may have provided Personal Information through the Site, please contact us at contact@arcusfoundation.org.
14. Changes to This Policy
We may update this Policy from time to time. If we make significant changes to our Policy, we will notify you. Arcus may update this Policy by posting a new version on this webpage.
15. Contact Us
For any questions you may have about this Privacy Policy or our data practices please email contact@arcusfoundation.org
Last Updated: October 2020
Home
About
Arcus Culture
Board & Staff
Contact
Employment
Grants
Country
AfghanistanÅland IslandsAlbaniaAlgeriaAmerican SamoaAndorraAngolaAnguillaAntarcticaAntigua and BarbudaArgentinaArmeniaArubaAustraliaAustriaAzerbaijanBahamasBahrainBangladeshBarbadosBelarusBelgiumBelizeBeninBermudaBhutanBoliviaBonaire, Sint Eustatius and SabaBosnia and HerzegovinaBotswanaBouvet IslandBrazilBritish Indian Ocean TerritoryBrunei DarussalamBulgariaBurkina FasoBurundiCambodiaCameroonCanadaCape VerdeCayman IslandsCentral African RepublicChadChileChinaChristmas IslandCocos IslandsColombiaComorosCongo, Democratic Republic of theCongo, Republic of theCook IslandsCosta RicaCôte d'IvoireCroatiaCubaCuraçaoCyprusCzech RepublicDenmarkDjiboutiDominicaDominican RepublicEcuadorEgyptEl SalvadorEquatorial GuineaEritreaEstoniaEswatini (Swaziland)EthiopiaFalkland IslandsFaroe IslandsFijiFinlandFranceFrench GuianaFrench PolynesiaFrench Southern TerritoriesGabonGambiaGeorgiaGermanyGhanaGibraltarGreeceGreenlandGrenadaGuadeloupeGuamGuatemalaGuernseyGuineaGuinea-BissauGuyanaHaitiHeard and McDonald IslandsHoly SeeHondurasHong KongHungaryIcelandIndiaIndonesiaIranIraqIrelandIsle of ManIsraelItalyJamaicaJapanJerseyJordanKazakhstanKenyaKiribatiKuwaitKyrgyzstanLao People's Democratic RepublicLatviaLebanonLesothoLiberiaLibyaLiechtensteinLithuaniaLuxembourgMacauMacedoniaMadagascarMalawiMalaysiaMaldivesMaliMaltaMarshall IslandsMartiniqueMauritaniaMauritiusMayotteMexicoMicronesiaMoldovaMonacoMongoliaMontenegroMontserratMoroccoMozambiqueMyanmarNamibiaNauruNepalNetherlandsNew CaledoniaNew ZealandNicaraguaNigerNigeriaNiueNorfolk IslandNorth KoreaNorthern Mariana IslandsNorwayOmanPakistanPalauPalestine, State ofPanamaPapua New GuineaParaguayPeruPhilippinesPitcairnPolandPortugalPuerto RicoQatarRéunionRomaniaRussiaRwandaSaint BarthélemySaint HelenaSaint Kitts and NevisSaint LuciaSaint MartinSaint Pierre and MiquelonSaint Vincent and the GrenadinesSamoaSan MarinoSao Tome and PrincipeSaudi ArabiaSenegalSerbiaSeychellesSierra LeoneSingaporeSint MaartenSlovakiaSloveniaSolomon IslandsSomaliaSouth AfricaSouth GeorgiaSouth KoreaSouth SudanSpainSri LankaSudanSurinameSvalbard and Jan Mayen IslandsSwedenSwitzerlandSyriaTaiwanTajikistanTanzaniaThailandTimor-LesteTogoTokelauTongaTrinidad and TobagoTunisiaTurkeyTurkmenistanTurks and Caicos IslandsTuvaluUgandaUkraineUnited Arab EmiratesUnited KingdomUnited StatesUruguayUS Minor Outlying IslandsUzbekistanVanuatuVenezuelaVietnamVirgin Islands, BritishVirgin Islands, U.S.Wallis and FutunaWestern SaharaYemenZambiaZimbabwe
Interest Area (select all that apply)*
LGBTQ Social Justice
Great Apes & Gibbons Conservation
What draws you to Arcus? (select all that apply)
I work in human rights.
I work in wildlife conservation.
I’m interested in the work of Arcus and its partners.
I’m interested in funding for my organization or project.
This iframe contains the logic required to handle Ajax powered Gravity Forms.
×
Arcus uses cookies to ensure we give you the best experience on our website and to effectively analyze site traffic.
Read our Privacy Policy and click to confirm your consent.
Accept
Privacy Overview
Strictly Necessary Cookies
Privacy Overview
This website uses cookies so that we can provide you with the best user experience possible. Cookie information is stored in your browser and performs functions such as recognising you when you return to our website and helping our team to understand which sections of the website you find most interesting and useful.
Strictly Necessary Cookies
Strictly Necessary Cookie should be enabled at all times so that we can save your preferences for cookie settings.
If you disable this cookie, we will not be able to save your preferences. This means that every time you visit this website you will need to enable or disable cookies again.
disable
Enable All
Save Changes
